<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sarah Schulte</title><link>https://sarah.engineer/</link><description>Recent content on Sarah Schulte</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 20:39:01 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sarah.engineer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Writing a Twitch Chatbot in Bash</title><link>https://sarah.engineer/posts/twitch-chat-bash/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 20:39:01 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://sarah.engineer/posts/twitch-chat-bash/</guid><description>One of the rites of passage for a programming Twitch streamer is building your own chat bot. There&amp;rsquo;s a plethora of tools and libraries available to make this task simpler; however, sometimes doing things the hard way is an opportunity to learn.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to do a deep dive into the implementation of my twitch chat bot, written in bash.
Getting Started My first step into this project was to consult Twitch&amp;rsquo;s docs.</description></item><item><title>Building a Game in 10 Days: How We Won a Game Jam</title><link>https://sarah.engineer/posts/fireside-jam-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 14:52:07 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sarah.engineer/posts/fireside-jam-2022/</guid><description>You can play our entry to the Fireside Game Jam 2022 here: PR Protector. It was rated #1 overall by the judges and other contestants of the jam.
After taking a break from game development for a while, I decided to enter a game jam with a few friends. We checked out the jam calendar on itch.io and found a casual looking 10-day jam called Fireside Jam 2022.
The starting day rolled around, and the theme was announced: Protect.</description></item><item><title>Simulating Multiplayer 3D Dice</title><link>https://sarah.engineer/posts/multiplayer-dice-physics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 22:30:07 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sarah.engineer/posts/multiplayer-dice-physics/</guid><description>I wanted to add 3D, physics-based dice to my online game, rolly cubes.
Synchronizing physics across an online multiplayer game is a non-trival challenge. Generally, it requires running the simulation on an authoritative game server and sending updates to the clients. I tried this approach at first, but I felt I was adding a lot of bloat to my otherwise lightweight server.
I found surprisingly little information for how people approached this particular problem in the past, so I wanted to write this blog post to document my solution in case it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to anyone else.</description></item><item><title>New Website</title><link>https://sarah.engineer/posts/new-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 20:39:01 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://sarah.engineer/posts/new-website/</guid><description>I decided to finally build a new website, using Hugo.
I have this tendency to fall down absurd rabbitholes while working on projects like this. In this case, it involved making the home page of my website contain a (very rough draft of a) POSIX-like shell. Check it out if you&amp;rsquo;re a nerd like me! Just press &amp;lsquo;enter&amp;rsquo; on the main page to activate it.
How it&amp;rsquo;s Built The crux of this shell is bash-parser, a repository I stumbled across on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://sarah.engineer/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sarah.engineer/about/</guid><description>Sarah Schulte is a software engineer with 5 years industry experience and an indie game developer.
She particularly enjoys playing tennis, pondering game design, and playing rhythm games (currently, mostly addicted to Beat Saber).
She also occasionally likes to stream on Twitch and write bad code (see: rolly cubes).
Currently&amp;hellip; Starting a new adventure in the world of indie game dev (stay tuned!) Building dumb things in bash</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://sarah.engineer/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sarah.engineer/contact/</guid><description>you found me!
send a message to:
easteregg [at] sarah [dot] engineer
to win absolutely nothing at all</description></item><item><title>qr</title><link>https://sarah.engineer/qr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sarah.engineer/qr/</guid><description>█▀▀▀▀▀█ ▀▀ ▀▄ █ █▀▀▀▀▀█ █ ███ █ █▄ █▀███ █ ███ █ █ ▀▀▀ █ ▀█▀▀▄▀█▀█ █ ▀▀▀ █ ▀▀▀▀▀▀▀ ▀▄▀▄▀ █▄█ ▀▀▀▀▀▀▀ ▀█▀▀▄ ▀▄█▄ ▀▀█▀ ▄▀▀▀▄▀ ▄█ █▄▀▀█▀ ▄▄▄▄ ▀█ █ ▄▄ ▀▀██▄▀ ▄▀▄█ ▀██▄▀███ ▀▀█ ▄▀▄▄▄ ▀▄▄▀▄ █▀█ █ ▄█ ▀▀▄ ▀ ▀▀█▀▄▀▄█▄▀█▀▀▀█▀█▀█ █▀▀▀▀▀█ ▄▀█▀▄ █ ▀ █ ▀██ █ ███ █ ▄▀█▀██ ▄▀██▀██▄█▄ █ ▀▀▀ █ █▄ ▀▀▀ ▀▀▀ █ █▀ ▀▀▀▀▀▀▀ ▀▀ ▀ ▀ ▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀</description></item></channel></rss>