<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Sarah Schulte</title><link>https://sarah.engineer/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Sarah Schulte</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 14:52:07 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sarah.engineer/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Game in 10 Days: How We Won a Game Jam</title><link>https://sarah.engineer/posts/fireside-jam-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 14:52:07 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sarah.engineer/posts/fireside-jam-2022/</guid><description>You can play our entry to the Fireside Game Jam 2022 here: PR Protector. It was rated #1 overall by the judges and other contestants of the jam.
After taking a break from game development for a while, I decided to enter a game jam with a few friends. We checked out the jam calendar on itch.io and found a casual looking 10-day jam called Fireside Jam 2022.
The starting day rolled around, and the theme was announced: Protect.</description></item><item><title>Simulating Multiplayer 3D Dice</title><link>https://sarah.engineer/posts/multiplayer-dice-physics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 22:30:07 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sarah.engineer/posts/multiplayer-dice-physics/</guid><description>I wanted to add 3D, physics-based dice to my online game, rolly cubes.
Synchronizing physics across an online multiplayer game is a non-trival challenge. Generally, it requires running the simulation on an authoritative game server and sending updates to the clients. I tried this approach at first, but I felt I was adding a lot of bloat to my otherwise lightweight server.
I found surprisingly little information for how people approached this particular problem in the past, so I wanted to write this blog post to document my solution in case it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to anyone else.</description></item><item><title>New Website</title><link>https://sarah.engineer/posts/new-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 20:39:01 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://sarah.engineer/posts/new-website/</guid><description>I decided to finally build a new website, using Hugo.
I have this tendency to fall down absurd rabbitholes while working on projects like this. In this case, it involved making the home page of my website contain a (very rough draft of a) POSIX-like shell. Check it out if you&amp;rsquo;re a nerd like me! Just press &amp;lsquo;enter&amp;rsquo; on the main page to activate it.
How it&amp;rsquo;s Built The crux of this shell is bash-parser, a repository I stumbled across on GitHub.</description></item></channel></rss>